<TABLE_DEFINITIONS Table="SAINC12" Name="Personal income change by component" Source="USDOC/BEA/RD"><LINE><Code>1</Code><Description>Percent change in personal income</Description><Definition>Consists of the income that persons receive in return for their provision of labor, land, and capital used in current production as well as other income, such as personal current transfer receipts. In the state and local personal income accounts the personal income of an area represents the income received by or on behalf of the persons residing in that area. It is calculated as the sum of wages and salaries, supplements to wages and salaries, proprietors' income with inventory valuation (IVA) and capital consumption adjustments (CCAdj), rental income of persons with capital consumption adjustment (CCAdj), personal dividend income, personal interest income, and personal current transfer receipts, less contributions for government social insurance plus the adjustment for residence.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2</Code><Description>Net earnings by place of residence contribution</Description><Definition>Consists of earnings by place of work less contributions for government social insurance plus the adjustment for residence.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>3</Code><Description>Dividends, interest, and rent contribution</Description><Definition>Consists of personal dividend income, personal interest income, and rental income of persons with capital consumption adjustment (CCAdj).</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>4</Code><Description>Personal current transfer receipts contribution</Description><Definition>Receipts of persons from government and business for which no current services are performed. Current transfer receipts from government include Social Security benefits, medical benefits, veterans' benefits, and unemployment insurance benefits. Current transfer receipts from business include liability payments for personal injury and corporate gifts to nonprofit institutions.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>5</Code><Description>Personal income dollar change (thousands)</Description><Definition>Consists of the income that persons receive in return for their provision of labor, land, and capital used in current production as well as other income, such as personal current transfer receipts. In the state and local personal income accounts the personal income of an area represents the income received by or on behalf of the persons residing in that area. It is calculated as the sum of wages and salaries, supplements to wages and salaries, proprietors' income with inventory valuation (IVA) and capital consumption adjustments (CCAdj), rental income of persons with capital consumption adjustment (CCAdj), personal dividend income, personal interest income, and personal current transfer receipts, less contributions for government social insurance plus the adjustment for residence.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>6</Code><Description>Net earnings by place of residence dollar change (thousands)</Description><Definition>Consists of earnings by place of work less contributions for government social insurance plus the adjustment for residence.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>7</Code><Description>Dividends, interest, and rent dollar change (thousands)</Description><Definition>Consists of personal dividend income, personal interest income, and rental income of persons with capital consumption adjustment (CCAdj).</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>8</Code><Description>Personal current transfer receipts dollar change (thousands)</Description><Definition>Receipts of persons from government and business for which no current services are performed. Current transfer receipts from government include Social Security benefits, medical benefits, veterans' benefits, and unemployment insurance benefits. Current transfer receipts from business include liability payments for personal injury and corporate gifts to nonprofit institutions.</Definition></LINE></TABLE_DEFINITIONS>
